Guide to the Livingston Family Papers
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
- Archibald R. Livingston Papers, 1880-1951; Series V; 3; (7 boxes) + 1 broadside folder
  Livingston summered in Newport, Rhode Island, as a youth; he and his older sister Anna (1866-1967) resided together all their adult lives, first in Colorado and with the military in California. After 1925, they spent summers at their home on Livingston Road, west of Medford, Oregon, and wintered in La Jolla. He died in Medford on August 3, 1952, and is buried in the Livingston family vault at Linlithgo, New York.
  The series contains a variety of personal papers, photographs, and ephemera documenting the life, primarily the military life, and interests of Archibald Livingston. The bulk of the material is graphic, and includes drawings, photographs, postcards, and prints, held in albums as well as grouped in folders. Many of the images show army installations and activities in Puerto Rico, Mexico, Colorado, California, and Europe, but Livingston was also a world traveler who made or collected photographs while in Hawaii, the Pacific Northwest, and South America. Archibald and Anna Livingston were both avid amateur photographers, often traveled together, and compiled photograph albums; but for their bookplates or handwritten captions, the albums look very similar. Readers should consult both siblings' series when looking for early twentieth-century images of the American West and Southwest.
  - Personal papers
    - Bank checks [cancelled], 1906-1924 (Box 37, Folder 312)
    - Correspondence, 1931-1951, undated (Box 37, Folder 313)
    - Drawings
      - Schematics of ship models, 1931
      - Miscellaneous sketches and maps, circa 1878-1943 (Box 37, Folder 314)
    - Ephemera, 1886-1941 (Box 37, Folder 315)
      Includes tennis and theater programs from Newport (1886-1887); school admission tickets and graduation invitation, Columbia University (1887-1891); American Society of Civil Engineers diploma (1939); Columbia alumni list (1941)
    - Financial papers, regarding family trusts, 1940-1947 (Box 37, Folder 316)
    - Legal papers, regarding family wills, 1944-1949 (Box 37, Folder 317)
    - Scrapbook, 1881-1887
      Contains Victorian-era scrap and holiday cards; photographs of St. Paul's School (Concord, New Hampshire) and fellow students there; Newport, Rhode Island; Grand Central Depot and the Chatham Museum, New York City; Stonehenge; the schooner Grayling; and unidentified scenes; etchings by F. S. Church, John Moran, Mary N. Moran, and Thomas Moran; small oil and watercolor paintings; portrait photograph of Anna P. Livingston (1881)
    - Scrapbook, 1901-1922 (Box 37, Folder 318-319)
      Contains newspaper clippings on miscellaneous subjects; second folder holds maritime images from Hawaii and other ephemeral items that were loose in the back of the scrapbook
    - Ship plans, blueprints (4) from the Historic American Merchant Marine Survey, circa 1936
    - Spelling book, 1880 (Box 37, Folder 320)
    - Writings, circa 1880, 1916 (Box 37, Folder 321)
      Includes "The Polar Sea" (childhood illustrated manuscript) and newspaper column
    - Veterans Administration paperwork, 1938-1942 (Box 37, Folder 322)
  - Military service papers
    - Pennsylvania National Guard: discharge papers, 1895 (Box 38, Folder 323)
      See also: Spanish-American War photograph album in Box 136
    - Spanish-American War
      - Leslie's Weekly, with feature on the Engineers corps and Puerto Rico, 1898 Oct 13
      - Newspaper clippings, 1898 (Box 38, Folder 324)
      - Photograph album: Puerto Rico and Pennsylvania, 1892-1898
        Images of Camp Townsend, Peekskill, New York (1898); sea voyage to Puerto Rico; military and civilian scenes on the island, particularly of Ponce (1898). Also includes images of ARL's service in the Pennsylvania National Guard at military camps at Montrose, Gettysburg, and Homestead (1892-1894).
      - Photographs: Philippines, circa 1898 (Box 38, Folder 325)
    - Colorado National Guard: Diary, photographs, and map of Big Bend District, Texas, 1915-1917 (Box 38, Folder 326)
      Includes snapshot photographs taken during General Pershing's Punitive Expedition into Mexico
    - World War I
      - "History of 115th Engineers" (two versions), undated (Box 38, Folder 327)
      - Maps and 40th Division personnel/ordnance table, 1918-1919
        Ten maps of France used by ARL during the war; includes General Pershing's Report (1918/1919)
      - Medallions and plaquettes, 1919, 1921, undated
        Nine commemorative bronze medallions and plaquettes in a viewing frame
      - Military manuals, 1917, 1918 (Box 38, Folder 328)
      - Newspaper clippings, 1917-1919 (Box 38, Folder 329)
      - Personnel paperwork, 1917-1919 (Box 38, Folder 330)
      - Photographs: France, Germany, and Luxembourg, 1918-1919 (Box 38, Folder 331-334)
        Includes military and civilian scenes in and around Hussigny, Coblenz, Pont à Mousson, and the Puvenelle forest in France; primarily unlabeled images, most taken by ARL, with some commercial postcards
      - Photographs: United States
        - California, San Diego, Balboa Park, circa 1917 (Box 39, Folder 335)
        - California, Camp Kearny, 1917-1918 (Box 39, Folder 336)
        - Colorado and California, miscellaneous, 1917-1920 (Box 39, Folder 337-338)
      - Viewbooks and postcard sets (Germany), circa 1919 (Box 39, Folder 339-340)
        Souvenirs of cities; includes "American Occupied Territory" viewbook
  - Photographs and prints
    Arranged under two headings: People and things; and Places.
    Photographs from Livingston's military career are with his Military Service Papers in Box 38.
    - People and things
      - Friends [school] and faculty members, 1887-1891, undated (Box 39, Folder 341)
        Primarily cabinet card portraits (individual and group) of Columbia University faculty and students, plus Philip Mercer Rhinelander (Harvard '91), a classmate at St. Paul's School
      - Cabinet card mailing boxes [from Sarony in New York and Ludovici in Newport], circa 1888 (Box 39, Folder 342)
      - Historic houses and buildings, circa 1880-1948 (Box 40, Folder 343-344)
        Includes early twentieth-century images of buildings in Philadelphia, Portsmouth, New Hampshire, Newport, Rhode Island, Washington, and Philadelphia. Similar material is filed in Series IV, Anna Livingston papers, Box 36, folders 300-301.
      - Livingston, Archibald R., circa 1891-1917 (Box 40, Folder 345)
      - Ship models [made by Livingston], undated (Box 40, Folder 346)
      - Ships, 1887-1917, undated (Box 40, Folder 347-348)
      - Unidentified, 1923, undated (Box 40, Folder 349)
    - Places
      Primarily photographs made by Archibald Livingston, but also includes commercial images, postcards, and some halftones images clipped from publications
      - Album: New York and the American West, 1889-1910, undated
        Includes Newport, Rhode Island; the Washington Arch (New York, 1889); Pan-American Exposition (Buffalo, 1901); the American West (1908-1910, undated)
      - Album: Colorado, Wyoming, Alaska, New York, and Canada, 1890-1897
        Includes the Columbia and Snake rivers, Manitou Springs, Yellowstone National Park; the Canadian Rockies (Alberta and British Columbia) (1891) and Quebec; Alaska; Niagara Falls (1897) and Cooperstown, New York (1890); Columbia University facilities; includes Columbia School of Mines students and fieldwork
      - Album: New Mexico, Mexico, and Colombia, 1891-1906
        Includes Tesuque Pueblo, New Mexico (1895); Zacatecas and other cities in Mexico (circa 1895 and 1906); Bogota, Medellin, Panama, Barranquilla, and other places in Colombia (1899); loose photographs of Wimer's Viaduct (1891) and other Mexican railroad images.
      - Album: American West, circa 1910
        Primarily unlabeled snapshots; includes Acoma Pueblo, New Mexico; Grand Canyon; Yosemite; unidentified mining town; redwood forest
      - Album: American West, 1915 (Box 40, Folder 350)
        Most images not labeled, but includes the area around the Cleveland Mine and Santa Rita, Stevens County, Washington
      - Album: American West, 1916 (Box 41, Folder 351)
        Most images not labeled, but includes Pecos Valley and Mission, New Mexico, and Rio Grande
      - Album: American West [otherwise unidentified], undated (Box 41, Folder 352)
      - Arizona and New Mexico, circa 1920 (Box 41, Folder 353)
      - California: La Jolla, 1920-1921 (Box 42, Folder 354)
      - California and the American West: miscellaneous, 1920-1929, undated (Box 42, Folder 355)
        Includes Atascadero, Mount Shasta, Ojai, San Diego, Santa Ynez; Yellowstone; also photographs by Stephen H. Willard of Palm Springs
      - Central America, circa 1920 (Box 42, Folder 356)
      - Colorado, 1913-circa 1920 (Box 42, Folder 357)
      - Europe, circa 1920 (Box 42, Folder 358)
      - Florida, undated (Box 42, Folder 359)
      - Hawaii, 1922 (Box 42, Folder 360-361)
        Includes commercial images by Williams Studio, Honolulu
      - Mexico, undated (Box 42, Folder 362)
      - Montana: Glacier National Park, circa 1920 (Box 42, Folder 363)
      - Morocco and Algeria, circa 1920 (Box 43, Folder 364-365)
      - New York State, 1920, undated (Box 43, Folder 366)
      - Oregon: Crater Lake, circa 1920 (Box 43, Folder 367)
      - Oregon: Jacksonville, Livingston home, 1922, undated (Box 43, Folder 368)
      - Oregon: miscellaneous, 1922, 1930, undated (Box 43, Folder 369)
      - Rhode Island: Newport, 1889-1890
      - Texas: Marfa, 1918 (Box 43, Folder 370)
        Photographs by Frank (Francis King) Duncan
      - Washington: Rainier National Park, undated (Box 43, Folder 371)
      - Washington: miscellaneous, 1922-1923 (Box 43, Folder 372)
      - Miscellaneous, 1923,1936, undated (Box 43, Folder 373)
        Includes images of Bermuda and British Columbia
      - Unidentified, 1923, undated (Box 43, Folder 374)
- Herman and Olga Kobbé Livingston Papers, 1897-1959; Series VI; 1; (3 boxes)
  Series VI is organized into three subseries: Correspondence, Personal Papers, and Photographs.
  Herman Livingston (1883–1951) and Olga Kobbé Livingston (1883–1968)
  Herman Livingston was the eldest of the three sons of Herman (1856-1936) and Emeline Hopkins Livingston, and inherited Oak Hill upon his father's death. Born at Oak Hill on August 18, 1883, he graduated from St. Paul's School in Concord, New Hampshire, in 1898, enrolled at Yale University in 1901, and the next year transferred to Williams College, from which he graduated in 1905. Livingston had a career as an insurance broker in New York City, and was an officer of the Paramount Oil Corporation (see Series X). On April 24, 1909, he married Olga Theodora Kobbé, daughter of Frederick W. and Louise Kobbé of New York. The couple lived for a period of time in Boston, but otherwise resided in New York City and at Oak Hill. Their only child, Alida Schuyler Livingston (1915-1940), a graduate of the Chapin School and Barnard College, was employed as a teacher at the former school when she died unexpectedly while visiting Victoria, British Columbia. She was memorialized through a Livingston exhibition held at the Columbia County (NY) Historical Society's House of History in 1941.
  Herman Livingston was a close friend of Major Charles White Whittlesey (1884-1921), the leader of the "Lost Battalion," whom he knew from their college days. Whittlesey's famed suicide note addressed to Livingston is not in the family papers, but there is a photograph of their college class (Box 46, folder 405) that Whittlesey had sent just months before he died; a letter from Whittlesey and clippings about him is filed in Series III, Herman and Emeline Livingston Papers.
  The series consists of business and personal correspondence of Herman Livingston Jr., with a few photographs filed at the end. Most of the correspondence concerns his career as an insurance broker, and the management of his and his family's finances, particularly as they related to the Oak Hill property and the Paramount Oil Company. The photographs are of the Livingstons' daughter Alida, and one each from St. Paul's School and Williams College; also here is a small album with images of a rustic retreat, perhaps the Balsam Lake Club, a fishing club in the western Catskills of which Livingston was a member.
  - Correspondence
    - Antiques, 1941-1962 (Box 44, Folder 375)
      Contains correspondence about Livingston family collections
    - Balsam Lake Club, 1928-1939 (Box 44, Folder 376)
    - Central New York Fur Company, 1928 (Box 44, Folder 377)
    - Columbia County Historical Society, 1940-1947 (Box 44, Folder 378)
    - Harrison and Carr, Ltd., 1920-1924 (Box 44, Folder 379)
    - Hopkins, Charles Vernon, 1918-1919 (Box 44, Folder 380)
    - Kobbé, Frederick William, 1919-1929 (Box 44, Folder 381)
      Contains transcript of Catherine Livingston letter which dates the building of Oak Hill at 1796
    - Livingston, Anna and Archibald [aunt and uncle], 1934-1947, undated (Box 44, Folder 382)
    - Livingston, Edmund P. (1889-1972) [brother], 1913-1918 (Box 44, Folder 383)
    - Livingston, Henry H. (1887-1960) [brother], 1908 Jul 10 (Box 44, Folder 384)
    - New England Mutual Life Insurance Company, 1928-1938 (Box 44, Folder 385)
    - Otheman & Swaim, 1938-1942 (Box 44, Folder 386)
    - Paramount Oil Company, 1928-1939 (Box 44, Folder 387)
    - Simmons, Bourne & Company, 1937-1939 (Box 44, Folder 388)
    - Business letters, 1915-1938 (Box 44, Folder 389)
    - Business letters, 1915-1938 (Box 45, Folder 390-392)
    - General correspondence, 1928-1962 (Box 45, Folder 393)
  - Personal papers
    - Big Indian Mountain Club, circa 1939 (Box 45, Folder 394)
    - Check registers, 1928-1931, 1941-1942 (Box 45, Folder 395-396)
    - Childhood drawing, circa 1900 (Box 45, Folder 397)
    - Condolence notes, 1937-1940 (Box 45, Folder 398)
    - Diploma, St. Paul's School, 1898
    - Estates of Herman and Emeline Livingston [parents], 1931-1944 (Box 45, Folder 399)
    - Insurance and investment papers, 1918 -1947, undated (Box 46, Folder 400)
    - Medical bills, 1927-1939 (Box 46, Folder 401)
    - Monogram transfer sets [for embroidery], circa 1920
    - Newspaper article about Oak Hill, 1952 Sep 28
    - Taxes and assessments, 1924-1950 (Box 46, Folder 402)
  - Photographs
    - Album of rural and woodland views [Balsam Lake Club?], undated (Box 46, Folder 403)
    - Livingston, Alida Schuyler (1915-1940) [daughter], circa 1916-1940 (Box 46, Folder 404)
    - St. Paul's School football team, 1897
    - Williams College classmates, circa 1905, circa 1920 (Box 46, Folder 405)
- Henry H. and Mary Eleanor Curran Livingston Papers, 1886-1969; Series VII; 5.5; (14 boxes)
  Series VII is organized into three subseries: Correspondence, Personal Papers, and Photographs.
  Henry H. Livingston (1887–1960)
  Henry Hopkins Livingston—called Bruddy (or Brud) by his family and Hank by his Yale classmates—was the son of Herman (1856-1936) and Emeline Cornell Hopkins Livingston. He was born on February 5, 1887, and prepared for college at the Taft School in Watertown, Connecticut. He graduated from Yale University in 1909; while there he played football, wrestled, and rowed, and was a member of Psi Upsilon and the Elihu Club. After college, Livingston went to work in West Virginia at the Louis F. Payn Oil Company's operation and, like his father, had investments in the maritime trade through the firm of Rogers & Webb. In 1916 he joined Francis C. Carr & Company insurance brokers of New York City. His career was interrupted during World War I when Livingston attended the United States Army's Officer's Training Camp at Plattsburg, New York, and served stateside in training assignments at military camps in Texas, Georgia, Ohio, and Iowa. In 1928 he became a partner in the New York office of the Philadelphia insurance firm of Lukens, Savage & Washburn, and remained with that company through his retirement in 1952. Livingston owned a yacht, the Eleanor, which he sailed on the Hudson and Lake Champlain, and rowed with various New York City groups, including the Nonpareil and Harlem rowing clubs. An invalid in his later years, he died on July 7, 1960, and was buried in the family vault at Linlithgo, New York.
  Mary Eleanor Curran Livingston (1884–1969)
  Mary Eleanor Curran was born in Englewood, New Jersey, on March 6, 1884, the daughter of John Elliot Curran and Eliza (Lilla) Phillips Mulford Curran (see Series XI). Known to family and friends as Eleanor, she graduated from the Dwight School, attended Smith College (1902-1904), taught privately (1904-1906), graduated from Barnard College (1908), and taught school until her marriage to Henry Livingston on June 26, 1916. The couple resided in New York City and at Oak Hill, and had three children: Henry Hopkins (1918-2008; see Series VIII), Eleanor Mulford (born March 15, 1920, graduated from Vassar College in 1941), and Herman II (1923-2007, Yale University Class of 1945W), all three of whom served in the military during World War II. Through her maternal ancestors Lion Gardiner and John Howland, Eleanor Livingston could claim membership in the Order of Colonial Lords of Manors, the Colonial Dames of America, and the Society of Mayflower Descendants; she died on April 27, 1969.
  The series contains the personal and family correspondence of Henry and Eleanor Livingston, with some personal papers and photographs. Three folder of Family Letters concern the management of co-owned investments and real estate, discussions of which also continue in Series VI, Herman Livingston Jr. Five folders of material document Livingston's employment with Lukens, Savage & Washburn, and six folders of letters between Henry and Eleanor Livingston cover homefront activities during their separations forced by World War I and Livingston's career. Like his father, Livingston also invested in four-masted merchant schooners through the firm of Rogers & Webb; two folders of correspondence and ship reports document his interests. His scrapbook (1906-1913) contains photographs of oil drilling installations in West Virginia and Ohio.
  - Correspondence
    - Curran, Eliza (Lilla) Phillips Mulford [mother], 1930-1936, undated (Box 47, Folder 406)
    - Curran, Henry H. [brother] and Fanny, 1905-1965, undated (Box 47, Folder 407-410)
    - Edmonds, Catharine Livingston [granddaughter], 1966-1968 (Box 47, Folder 411)
    - Frick Art Reference Library, 1957-1960 (Box 47, Folder 412)
    - Hopkins, Charles Vernon, 1919 Jan 4 (Box 47, Folder 413)
    - Livingston, Anna P. (1866-1967) [aunt], 1920-1965 (Box 47, Folder 414-415)
      See also: Box 51, folders 448-450
    - Livingston, Archibald R. (1868-1952) [uncle], 1916, 1941 (Box 48, Folder 416)
    - Livingston, Edmund P. (1889-1972) [brother], 1954-1960 (Box 48, Folder 417)
    - Livingston, Eleanor Mulford (b. 1920) [daughter], 1931-1932, undated (Box 48, Folder 418)
    - Livingston, Henry H. and Mary Eleanor [letters between], 1918-1939 (Box 48, Folder 419-423)
    - Livingston, Henry H. and Mary Eleanor [letters between], 1940-1955, undated (Box 49, Folder 424)
    - Livingston, Henry H. (1918-2008) [son] and Maria, 1919-1966 (Box 49, Folder 425)
    - Livingston, Henry H. III [grandson], 1967-1970 (Box 49, Folder 426-427)
    - Livingston, Herman (1856-1936) [father] and Emeline, 1918-1932 (Box 49, Folder 428)
    - Livingston, Herman Jr. (1883-1951) [brother], 1916 Nov 9 (Box 49, Folder 429)
    - Livingston, Herman II (1923-2007) [son] and Janet, 1923-1969 (Box 49, Folder 430)
    - Livingston, Isabel [granddaughter], 1965-1968 (Box 49, Folder 431-433)
    - Livingston, John C. (1862-1956) [uncle], 1945, 1954, undated (Box 50, Folder 434)
    - Livingston, Richard [grandson], 1965-1969 (Box 50, Folder 435)
    - Lukens, Savage & Washburn, 1928-1959 (Box 50, Folder 436-440)
      Includes company annual and financial reports
    - Metropolitan Museum of Art, 1962-1963 (Box 51, Folder 441)
    - Rogers & Webb, 1914-1930 (Box 51, Folder 442-443)
    - Sellers, Charles Coleman, 1957-1958 (Box 51, Folder 444)
    - Thrall, Miriam, 1957-1963 (Box 51, Folder 445)
    - Wilkinson, Katharine, 1956-1958 (Box 51, Folder 446)
    - World War I letters from friends, 1918-1919 (Box 51, Folder 447)
      Includes two from Laurance I. Neale
    - Family correspondence, re: real estate and investments, 1931-1952 (Box 51, Folder 448-450)
      Includes letters circulated among Herman, Henry, Edmund, Anna, and Archibald Livingston, and Sarah (Sallie) Livingston Williams, and a survey map of Oak Hill property (1948)
    - General correspondence, 1911-1969 (Box 52, Folder 451-454)
  - Personal papers
    - Beekeeping ephemera, 1931-1954 (Box 52, Folder 455)
    - Clippings files, 1917, 1930s-1940s (Box 52, Folder 456-462)
      Filed by topic: Automobiles and Trains; Boats; Family History; People; World War I; Yale and Crew; and Miscellaneous
    - Cunningham family history, 1947-1951, undated (Box 53, Folder 463)
    - Estates of Henry H. and Fanny Curran, 1967 (Box 53, Folder 464)
    - Insurance claims, appraisals, and paperwork, 1929-1959 (Box 53, Folder 465)
    - Livingston, Eleanor Mulford (b. 1920) [daughter]
      - Childhood ephemera, drawings, and writings, 1920-1930 (Box 53, Folder 466)
      - Postcard collection, 1928-1935, undated (Box 53, Folder 467)
    - Livingston, Henry H.
      - Awards and medals, for rowing and marksmanship, 1909-1918 (Box 53, Folder 468-469)
      - Diaries (3), 1900-1908 (Box 53, Folder 470)
      - Essay on merchant ship Tonquin, undated (Box 53, Folder 471)
      - Financial account book, 1912 (Box 53, Folder 472)
      - Financial papers, 1911-1966 (Box 53, Folder 473)
      - Scrapbook, 1906-1913 (Box 54)
        Photographs, school grade reports, programs, memorabilia covers Yale University years, including crew and wrestling teams (programs, photographs, and newspaper clippings) and Elihu Club; also includes post-college ephemera, photographs, and clippings regarding: the Harlem River Rowing Club (including regattas in New York, Philadelphia, and Boston); oil fields in Ambler, West Virginia, and Rio Grande, Ohio; snapshots of yachts and schooners, friends, and landscapes along the Hudson River and at Oak Hill.
      - Ship prints and photographs, undated (Box 55, Folder 474)
      - Taft School yearbook, 1903 (Box 55, Folder 475)
      - Will and estate papers, 1958-1962 (Box 55, Folder 476-478)
        Contains an accounting of Mary Eleanor Curran Livingston's career
      - Miscellaneous papers, clippings, and ephemera, 1887-1940, undated (Box 55, Folder 479-480)
    - Livingston, Mary Eleanor Curran
      - Address books, 1954, undated (Box 55, Folder 481-482)
      - Barnard College yearbook and ephemera, 1908 (Box 56, Folder 483-484)
      - Birthday book, undated (Box 56, Folder 485)
      - Curran family cemetery records, 1928-1966 (Box 56, Folder 486)
      - Engagement and wedding announcements, 1915-1916 (Box 56, Folder 487)
      - Funeral guest register, 1969 (Box 56, Folder 488)
      - Heritage societies, 1938-1959, undated (Box 56, Folder 489-491)
      - Postcards [collected, unused], undated (Box 57, Folder 492-493)
      - Theater programs, 1932-1946 (Box 57, Folder 494)
      - Wedding gifts register, 1916 (Box 57, Folder 495)
      - Miscellaneous papers, 1889-1969, undated (Box 57, Folder 496)
    - Livingston, Herman II (1923-2007) [son]: World War II ephemera and photographs, 1944, undated (Box 57, Folder 497)
    - Marriage and baptism records, 1945 (Box 57, Folder 498)
    - Oak Hill Iron Mining Company, 1961-1962 (Box 57, Folder 499)
  - Photographs
    - Livingston children, circa 1918-1946 (Box 57, Folder 500)